Lothar Wolff collection, 1926-1987
George Eastman Museum
- Series 2, Film/TV Projects, 1932-1986
  - Subseries 8, National Geographic Society Films [General], 1973-1983
    - no title (Box C355)
      - [Red 3-ring binder with tape label on spine "Paris, Munich, Hamburg/NGS/Kane Jan. Feb. 76"], 1976 (Folder 41)
        Lists of Paris screenings with notations; Paris screening reports, many with synopses of the films attached [in French]; "Result of Paris Screenings OPOP" document; Munich screening reports with synopses attached [in German, English]; list of films screened in Hamburg; Hamburg screening reports with synopses [in English]; related correspondence.
  - Subseries 9,Other People, Other Places, 1971-1975; 1980
    - no title (Box C301)
      - Richard Price Television Associates, Correspondence, 1975 (Folder 65)
        Correspondence and press materials related to natural history documentaries,Other People, Other Places from Richard Price Television Associates Ltd., International Television Programming.
    - no title (Box C310)
      - "The People of Asia" TV Series Planned?, 1969; 1975-1977 (Folder 12)
        List of possible subjects for Other People, Other Places III.
    - no title (Box C314)
      - Other People, Other Places– Budgets, Schedules etc., 1975 (Folder 1)
        "Delivery Dates" calendars; handwritten notes on cost estimates; line budgets; adding machine tape with budget totals; program routine; "El Hombre Y la Tiera Series" titles list.
      - Other People, Other Places-- Budget Plans for Each Part of Series, 1973-1975 (Folder 2)
        Red binder containing Other People, Other Places Program routine dated 8/17/1973; accounting sheets for each episode from seasons 1 and 2.
      - OPOP-- Viewer Letters Other People -- Other Places, 1973-1975 (Folder 3)
        Correspondence (inquiries, feedback, etc.).
      - Other People, Other Places-- Screenings in Europe (LIST), 1974 (Folder 4)
        Lists of potential Other People, Other Places Series 2 segments to be screened while in Europe.
      - Other People, Other Places-- Screening Schedules & Formats, 1973-1975 (Folder 5)
        Correspondence; segment production/completion/delivery schedules; memos regarding syndication format for World of Survival and Other People, Other Places; production charts.
      - Other People, Other Places: Post Production Script for The Arctic& Letters, 1973-1974 (Folder 6)
        Telegram blank regarding "Beyond the North Circle"; "Post Production Script to the Film ‘The Arctic’"; outline of the film The Longest Night – Diary of an Explorer with notes from Wolff; proposal for an Antarctic film series.
      - Other People, Other Places("Basque Sheepherder," "The Parachutist," "Pilgrims of Water," "Fabulous Lands of the Persian Gulf," "Driving into Danger," Introduction by Peter Graves), 1974-1975 (Folder 7)
        Peter Graves' intro/conclusion texts and revisions; related memo.
      - Other People, Other Places Forgotten Wilderness, 1974 (Folder 8)
        Correspondence regarding Stan Brock’s film Forgotten Wilderness; publicity brochure.
      - Other People, Other Places: Proposal for "The People of Iceland,", 1973-1974 (Folder 9)
        Segment proposal, budget.
      - Other People, Other Places: "The World About Us: Arctic Doctor" (Post Production Script) A BBC-Time-Life Co-Production, 1974 (Folder 10)
        Post-production script for segment of Other People, Other Places[aka The World Around Us,Life Around Us] (note:The World About Us is the BBC series from which many segments of The World Around Us were adapted).
      - Other People, Other Places-- Screenings in Hamburg, Germany to Buy Films, 1973-1975 (Folder 11)
        Report folder containing outlines of documentary series segments available from Polytel International Film-und-Fernsehen GmbH; screening reports; correspondence [in English, German] regarding German TV series about Antarctica; newspaper clippings; outline [in French] of "Mad Zoo/Neurotic Zoo" film project.
      - Other People, Other Places-- Screenings in London, 1974-1975 (Folder 12)
        Correspondence regarding films for potential adaptation; screening reports in Wolff’s hand of various documentaries [program candidates for series III]; documentary films press materials; list of films by Hugh Gibb; materials about alpine kiting; outlines of TV series Sink or Swim and Frontiers of Time; magazine article about poaching in African game preserves.
      - Other People, Other Places-- Screenings in Paris to Buy Films, 1973-1975 (Folder 13)
        Screening reports in Wolff’s hand of various documentary program candidates for series III; press materials for various documentary films; correspondence regarding films and film screenings in Paris; newspaper clipping.
      - Other People, Other Places-- Screening Reports from Rome -- Italian Productions, 1974-1975 (Folder 14)
        Notes about screened films; business card; sources and contact info; newspaper clipping regarding sinking cities; synopses of Italian produced documentaries with handwritten notes; screening reports of various documentary program candidates for series III; correspondence [in English, French] regarding screening arrangements.
      - Other People, Other Places-- Correspondence for Screening Arrangements, 1973-1975 (Folder 15)
        Spiral secretary pad: "Screenings OPOP I/1973" screening notes for program candidates; program candidate outlines; correspondence regarding possible OPOP program scripts, prints for screenings, screening arrangements in London, Hamburg, Paris.
      - Other People, Other Places-- Ratings and Publicity, Some with Wild, Wild World of Animals, 1974-1975 (Folder 16)
        Correspondence regarding ratings, viewer response; Nielsen ratings charts; syndication reports;Variety"Prime-Access Reviews".
      - Other People, Other Places-- Letters, Plans for 3 Series (Misc.), 1974-1975 (Folder 17)
        Correspondence regarding episode candidates [English, German]; screening reports; film synopses/outlines; magazine article regarding Patagonia exploration; 2/74 UNESCO Courier magazine; OPOP II Completion Schedule;NYT clipping regarding Icelandic volcanic explosion.
      - Other People, Other Places-- Misc. Correspondence, 1971; 1973-1975 (Folder 18)
        3x5 card specifying ad placement; agreements regarding licensing and delivery of series segments; delivery schedules; London screening schedule of potential series segments; correspondence and drafts regarding licensing agreements, employee vacation time, disposition of files, writers' fees for Wild, Wild World of Animals; music cue sheet; pro-forma documents including standard release forms, invoices; newspaper clipping regarding unskilled Brazilian labor; news release and clipping [photocopy] regarding Freeport Mining; list of potential Other People, Other Places II hosts.
      - Other People, Other Places-- Production in Hollywood, 1973-1974 (Folder 19)
        Correspondence and documents related to production costs of OPOP segments.
      - Letters & List of Titles of Other People, Other Places Series I, II concerning reissue, 1980 (Folder 20)
        Correspondence regarding list of OPOP titles and possibility of a series repackaging/reissue dated June 4, 1980.
      - Wild, Wild World of Animals, 1973 (Folder 27)
        Promotional material and correspondence;Variety ad for SAL wildlife TV programming;New York Times TV listings with ads for Strange Places and Wild, Wild World of Animals;Los Angeles Times TV listings page; issues of Time, Inc. newsletter F.Y.I..
      - WWWOA Viewer Letters Wild, Wild World of Animals, 1973-1974 (Folder 29)
        Correspondence includes one letter regarding Other People, Other Places.
      - Offer to Lothar Wolff to produce Other People, Other Places(Time/Life), 1974 (Folder 35)
        Offer letter from Bruce L. Paisner dated 2/20/1974.
    - no title (Box C355)
      - [Red 3-ring binder with tape label on spine "Paris, Munich, Hamburg/NGS/Kane Jan. Feb. 76"], 1976 (Folder 41)
  - Subseries 10,A Parade of Witnesses, 1953; 1979-1983
    - no title (Box C300)
      - [Binder labeled "Parade of Witnesses," Oct./Nov. 83], 1983 (Folder 1)
        Yellow binder contains photographs and photo negatives, pamphlets, and A Parade of Witnesses production information.
    - no title (Box C308)
      - Miscellaneous material and letters concerning Martin Luther, 1980 (Folder 4)
    - no title (Box C368)
      - A Parade of Witnesses-- script, director Paul Lammers, 1983 (Folder 3)
      - A Parade of Witnesses-- Exposé by Allan Shore, 1982 (Folder 4)
      - A Parade of Witnesses-- Script by Allan Shore, 1983 (Folder 5)
      - A Parade of Witnesses-- Misc. Correspondence, 1983 (Folder 6)
      - A Parade of Witnesses-- Scripts, Notes, etc., 1982-1983 (Folder 7)
      - A Parade of Witnesses-- Material and Articles on Martin Luther, 1982-1983 (Folder 8)
      - Martin Luther, Jubilee -- A 500th Birthday Media Festival -- "The Hammer and the Pen,", 1983 (Folder 9)
      - Material on Martin Luther -- Letters, Newspaper Articles, 1965; 1982-1983 (Folder 10)
      - "Martin Luther": Treatment for a BBC Production, 1983 (Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous for "Martin Luther" Special, 1979-1983 (Folder 12)
      - Media Opportunities for the 500th Anniversary of the Birth of Martin Luther, ca. 1983 (Folder 14)
  - Subseries 11,Planet Earth/Planet Earth Revisited, 1960-1963; 1979-1983
    - no title (Box 301)
      - Lazi Film-- Lothar Wolff, 1982-1983 (Folder 45)
        Correspondence regarding "the Ecology project"; a sequel series to Planet Earth
      - Wally Nielsen, 1981 (Folder 54)
        Business correspondence regarding Planet Earth Revisited project, etc.
    - no title (Box C352B)
      - [American Film Festival Blue Ribbon Award for "Magnetic Force"], 1962
        Blue ribbon embedded in 3 1/2" x 2 1/2" clear plastic.
    - no title (Box C371)
      - Georgeann Kane--Planet Earth, 1981 (Folder 1)
        Correspondence with Georgeann Kane and a questionnaire regarding "Planet Earth Revisited."
      - Material on Planet Earth-- Series -- National Academy of Sciences, ca. 1960 (Folder 2)
        Brochure
      - Planet Earth-- "The Nearest Star" -- Script, 1960 (Folder 3)
        Script for segment "The Nearest Star" aka "Our Nearest Star" dated August 3, 1960.
      - Planet Earth-- P.R. Material, ca. 1960 (Folder 4)
        Promotional brochure, catalog of 16mm earth sciences films from McGraw-Hill, including the Planet Earth series.
      - "Planet Earth Revisited,", 1980-1981 (Folder 5)
        Travel vouchers and expense reports related to work with the National Academy of Sciences.
      - "Planet Earth Revisited" --WQED, Pittsburgh, 1980-1981 (Folder 9)
        Includes proposed budgets, correspondence with Linda Reavely and University of Arizona dean Hugh Odishaw.
      - Presentation on "Planet Earth Revisted,", ca. 1980 (Folder 10)
        Includes first outline of presentation and drafts of episodes.
      - "Planet Earth Revisted" --Stephan Chodorov, 1981-1982 (Folder 11)
        Correspondence.
      - "Planet Earth Revisited" -- Interim Proposals/Reports, 1981 (Folder 12)
        "Planet Earth Revisited" reports and proposals, as well as materials related to proposed series "Then and Now," including series overview, brochures, correspondence/memos, interim report.
      - Planet Earth Revisited-- Contracts, Correspondence, etc., 1979-1982 (Folder 13)
        Includes contracts, correspondence with various universities and scientific research institutions, screening reports, clippings, "agreement language" from WQED.
      - Planet Earth Revisited--WQED Expenses, 1981-1982 (Folder 14)
        Records of expenses incurred, including phone charges, shipping charges, lodging, airline ticket receipts.
      - "Terra Nova -- The Rediscovery of Planet Earth,", 1982 (Folder 15)
        Correspondence with Georgeann Kane and proposal for Planet Earth Revisited under the working title "Terra Nova: Rediscovery of Earth" (see notation on document in Box C371, Folder 10).
      - "IGY -- Planet Earth Revisited,", 1960-1961; 1979-1981 (Folder 17)
        Materials related to Planet Earth and proposed series "Planet Earth Revisted." Includes 1960 press pelePase for Planet Earth; 1961 Planet Earth distribution report; "Planet Earth Revisited" questionnaire (copy of document found in Box C371, Folder 1),; correspondence; notes; inventories; outline; minutes from the Geophysics Research Board meeting and Geophysics Film Series Committee agenda; information on WQED and contact information. Materials removed from original binder Spring 2014.
      - [Binder labeled "Planet Earth Material at Bonded Film Storage Vaults"], 1963 (Folder 18)
        Catalog contains "Master Contents List of Cartons," "Detailed Listing of Can Contents by Film Title," and "List of Original Formerly at Color Service Laboratory Now Stored at Bonded."
      - [Binder labeled "Planet Earth Revisited-- Outlines, etc."], 1980-1981 (Folder 19)
        Includes proposed episode outlines, drafts, correspondence, notes, basic program overviews. Also includes Wolff's summary of the proposed series and its eventual production by WQED under the title Planet Earth.
      - [Unlabeled binder, "Planet Earth Revisited" material], 1981 (Folder 20)
        Drafts, notes, research materials, clippings, memos, correspondence, potential images for the opening sequence, possible subject breakdown for the series. Many documents are summaries of interviews. Includes correspondence with Hugh Odishaw,Stephan Chodorov, and Georgann Kane.
  - Subseries 12,Question 7, 1961-1962
    - no title (Box C019)
      - [California Federation of Women’s Clubs Motion Picture Award for Question 7], 1961 (Folder 1)
        Certificate awarded to Louis de Rochemont Associates and producer Lothar Wolff.
      - [11th Berlin International Film Festival Award for Question 7], 1961
        Bronze plate. Award for "Best Feature Film Suitable for Young People."
    - no title (Box C262)
      - [Two awards from the Office Catholique International du Cinema], undated
        Two bronze ships in wooden cases -- one opening horizontally, the other vertically -- from the Office Catholique International du Cinema. No film title is inscribed, but a photo in Box C356, Folder 9 depicts "M. Monaco" receiving the vertical case from the OCIC for Question 7.
    - no title (Box C300)
      - [Unlabeled Question 7 photo album], ca. 1961; 1969 (Folder 4)
        Photographs taken during the production of Question 7. Subjects include Wolff; director Stuart Rosenberg; the town of Mölln, Germany. Also includes 1969 New York Times clippings regarding the trial of West German spy Heinz Suetterlin.
    - no title (Box C352B)
      - [Interfilm Award], 1962
        Four-inch wooden award, most likely for Question 7(a 1962 Interfilm award certificate for Question 7 was found in Box C368). Original inventory states this is in three pieces but there is only one.
    - no title (Box C356)
      - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1930-1960; 1971-1972; ca. 1983; undated (Folder 14)
        Black-and-white photograph of Wolff and Lutheran Film Associates president Paul C. Empie signing a Question 7 production contract, undated; Wolff and Robert E. A. Lee at a 1972 ceremony commemorating Question 7.
    - no title (Box C368)
      - [Newspaper Clippings, 1951-1966] (Folder 16)
        Newspaper clippings regarding Windjammer.
    - no title (Box C368)
      - Shooting Schedule (Detailed) for Question 7-- D: Stuart Rosenberg and Daily Production Record, ca. 1961 (Folder 17)
        The shooting schedule is bound in a brown book. The production record is slipped in the front.
      - [Interfilm Award for Question 7], 1962 (Folder 18)
        Award certificate.
      - Question 7, ca. 1961 (Folder 19)
        Two undated black-and-white contact sheets of photos featuring composer Hans-Martin Majewski, production assistant Michael Roemer, Mrs. Roemer and son; all identified by captions on reverse in Wolff's hand. Additional captions read "Question 7" and "New Hamburg."
  - Subseries 13,The Roman Spring of Mrs. Stone, 1961; 1979
    - no title (Box C300)
      - [Photo album labeled "Rome, 1961"],"] (Folder 2)
        Photographs from the production of The Roman Spring of Mrs. Stone, including photos of Vivien Leigh,Warren Beatty, and Jill St. John. The separately foldered album page consisting of 12 small black-and-white photographs -- some of which were enlarged and included in this album -- was originally located in "Misc. Photographs," Box 356, Folder 9.
    - no title (Box C367)
      - Clipping on The Roman Spring of Mrs. Stone(1961) from The New Yorker, 1979 (Folder 22)
        "Goings on about Town" column featuring an abridged version of Pauline Kael’s negative review.
  - Subseries 14,Sky's the Limit, 1969-1985
    - [Photo album labeled " 1983 The Sky’s the Limit France & US"] (Folder 7)
      Color photos taken during the production of The Sky’s the Limit. Subjects include Wolff, production crew, balloonists and balloon events,Malcolm Forbes,Nicole Jouve, flooding of the Seine. Also includes clipping from National Geographic magazine.
    - no title (Box C301)
      - Lazi Film(Tim Cowling,National Geographic Society), 1981-1983 (Folder 39)
        Letter from producer Heinz von Matthey at Franz Lazi Film to Tim Cowling regarding "From Montgolfiere to Satellite."
      - Sigaar, Jacqueline (Paris), 1977; 1983 (Folder 68)
    - no title (Box C313)
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- 1. Draft, 1983 (Folder 1)
        Outline draft.
      - The Sky’s the Limit: Rough Outline, ca. 1983 (Folder 2)
        Early outline.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Script Development, 1983 (Folder 3)
        Includes correspondence with Wolff.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Scripts, Changes, ca. 1983 (Folder 4)
        Includes correspondence with Wolff's production company through Sue Becker.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Pre-Final Draft, 1983 (Folder 5)
        Pre-final draft.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Pre-Final Script, 1983 (Folder 6)
        Pre-final script.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Final Script, 1984 (Folder 7)
        Also includes correspondence between Wolff and the National Geographic Society.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Diverse Scripts, 1983 (Folder 8)
        Scripts with notes.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Checker Notes --NGS, 1983 (Folder 9)
        Correspondence and "checker notes" involving National Geographic Society.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Shot List, ca. 1983 (Folder 10)
        Undated shot list.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Shot Sheets, ca. 1983 (Folder 11)
        Lists of numbered camera shots with descriptions.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Opening Titles, 1984 (Folder 12)
        Main titles with note to Sue Becker.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- The Balloon Intercomparison Campaign -- Palestine, Texas, April, 1983 (Folder 13)
        Newspaper article, background information, and two photos from the Jet Propulsion Laboratory at California Institute of Technology.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Production in France, 1983 (Folder 14)
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Chateau de Balleroy, 1983 (Folder 15)
        Program, schedule, copy of Forbes magazine supplement, pamphlets, notes, and name tag for Wolff. Materials in English and French.
      - The Sky’s the Limit--Pierre Levie, 1983 (Folder 16)
        Correspondence with Pierre Levie, reference materials related to ballooning. Materials in English and French.
      - The Sky’s the Limit--Société française de production et de création audiovisuelles, 1983 (Folder 17)
        Includes correspondence with the National Geographic Society.
      - The Sky’s the Limit to Jacqueline Sigaar, 1983 (Folder 18)
        Correspondence with Jacqueline Sigaar along with her CV. In English and French.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Correspondence, 1980; 1983-1984 (Folder 19)
        Correspondence mostly related to invoices, permissions, and film rights. Materials are in English, German, and French.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Credits, 1983 (Folder 20)
        Drafts for main and end titles.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Source Lists, ca. 1983 (Folder 21)
        Shot list with footage/image sources with letter from Sue Becker to Wolff.
      - Lab report for The Sky’s the Limit, 1984 (Folder 22)
        Lab report on the condition of the print from Commonwealth Films.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Rights, 1983-1985 (Folder 23)
        Includes correspondence regarding rights and permissions; invoices; agreements; scene list; checks. Materials are in English and French.
      - National Archives -- Ballooning Footage --The Sky’s the Limit, ca. 1983 (Folder 24)
        List of balloon footage from the National Archives, photographic services price quote request form.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Correspondence with NGS, 1983-1984 (Folder 25)
        Correspondence with the National Geographic Society and Société française de production et de création audiovisuelles[co-producer]. Topics include shooting locations and the arrival of film. In English and French.
      - The Sky’s the Limit--American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics Annual Meeting and Technical Display -- Report, 1983 (Folder 26)
        Report of May 10-12, 1983, meeting in Long Beach, CA.
      - Outlines The Sky’s the Limit, ca. 1983 (Folder 27)
        Program outlines and scene timings.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Picture Material, 1983 (Folder 28)
        Pamphlet for "The Balloon: A Bicentennial Exhibition" dated 10/1/1983; photographs; article on ballooning history from unknown publication; pamphlet from the Chateau de Balleroy; copies of historical illustrations; prints of various forms of flight.
      - Precision Labs-- Bills The Sky’s the Limit, ca. 1983 (Folder 29)
        Bills and comparison of film elements from Precision Film Laboratories, Inc.
      - Misc. Articles on Ballooning The Sky’s the Limit, 1981-1983 (Folder 30)
        Brochures, one scanned copy of a brochure, Projects in Field Archaeology Activities Report, research materials. Names appearing in this folder are Xandra Hemmes of The Bombard Society(commercial ballooning excursions) and Sue Becker of Lothar Wolff Productions.
      - Budget --NGS The Sky’s the Limit, ca. 1983 (Folder 31)
        Undated production budget breakdown, with addendum.
      - The Sky’s the Limit-- Authorization for Unclassified Stock Footage Release from Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense, 1983 (Folder 32)
        Includes document of authorization signed by William J. Hudson.
      - Facts The Sky’s the Limit, ca. 1983 (Folder 33)
        Notes about Jet Propulsion Laboratory balloon launches.
      - Etc...The Sky’s the Limit Misc. Letters, 1983 (Folder 34)
        Correspondence, list of films and permissions. Correspondents include All Nations Forwarding Co. Inc.(Import Company, Inc.),Mary Evans Picture Library;Ballooning: The Journal of the Balloon Federation of America.
      - Notes The Sky’s the Limit, ca. 1983 (Folder 35)
        Handwritten notes about balloons.
      - Gene Sheppard's Info about Balloons for The Sky’s the Limit, 1974; 1983 (Folder 36)
        Correspondence with E.E. Sheppard(Department of the Air Force) and Sue Becker; "Summary of Tethered-Lighter-Than-Air Development Conducted by the Range Measurements Laboratory" dated September 27, 1974.
      - Booklets about Ballooning for The Sky’s the Limit, 1983-1984 (Folder 37)
        Booklets and scene list.
      - Screening Reports The Sky’s the Limit, ca. 1983 (Folder 38)
        Reports for various pieces of footage.
      - "Balloon" Negative for The Sky’s the Limit, 1983 (Folder 39)